Sometimes in April is a drama, history, war film directed by Raoul Peck.
Two brothers are divided by marriage and fate during the 100
horrifying days of the 1994 Rwandan genocide.
Augustin, played by Idris Elba.
Jeanne, played by Carole Karemera.
Martine, played by Pamela Nomvete.
Honoré, played by Oris Erhuero.
Xavier, played by Fraser James.
Colonel Bagosora, played by Abby Mukiibi Nkaaga.
Sometimes in April is a 2005 American made-for-television historical drama film about the 1994
Rwandan Genocide, written and directed by the Haitian filmmaker Raoul Peck.
The ensemble cast includes Idris Elba, Oris Erhuero,
Carole Karemera, and Debra Winger.
The story centers around Augustin Muganza, a moderate Hutu military captain who struggles to find closure after bearing witness to the killing
of nearly 1 million Tutsis and moderate Hutus in 100 days, while becoming divided by politics and losing some of his own family.
The film intersperses between the genocide in 1994, and April 2004, when Augustin is invited by his
brother, Honoré Butera, to visit him as he stands trial for his involvement in the genocide.
In addition to Augustin's tribulations, the film depicts the attitudes and circumstances leading up to the outbreak of brutal violence, the
intertwining stories of people struggling to survive genocide, and the aftermath as the survivors try to find justice and reconciliation.
The story is also intercut with scenes of Prudence Bushnell, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for African Affairs for American President Bill
Clinton, and her failed attempts to stop the genocide and advise the American government and public to acknowledge the unfolding genocide.
The film was nominated for multiple awards, including a Primetime Emmy Award nomination for Outstanding Music
Composition for a Miniseries, Movie, or Special to the composer of the film, Bruno Coulais.
It is one of the first large-scale films about the
genocide to be filmed in Rwanda.
The film explores themes of destruction of a civilization,
africa, rwanda, hutu, based on true story.
The tone is emotional.